The rosmsg info command prints out message type information to the console.
rosmsg info コマンドでは コンソールにメッセージ形式で情報を出力できます
Let's get more information about the cmd_vel topic.
cmd_vel トピックについて さらに情報を取得してみましょう
First, I am going to clear the terminal,
まずはターミナルをクリアします
and then I am going to use the command rosmsg show
それからコマンド rosmsg show
and then the name of the package containing the message type.
メッセージタイプを指定したパッケージの名前を入力します
In this case, it's geometry_msgs/Twist as we saw a moment ago,
この場合は 少し前に見たばかりですが
forward slash and finally twist,
geometry_msgs/Twist ですね
the name of the message type and there we have it.
メッセージタイプの名前を入力して このとおり
The full message definition for the twist type.
Twist タイプのメッセージの完全な定義です
You can see from the command output that the twist message
コマンド出力から Twist メッセージは
is composed of two messages of type vector three.
Vector3 タイプの 2 つのメッセージで構成されているのがわかります
A type that is also defined in the geometry messages package.
geometry_msgs パッケージでもタイプは定義されています
There's one three dimensional vector for linear velocity and one for angular velocity.
線形速度に対して 3 次元ベクトルが 1 つと 角速度が 1 つあります
Each vector consists of three different 64 bit floating point components, component x,
それぞれのベクトルは 3 つの 64 ビット浮動小数点コンポーネントから構成されています
y and z. Float64 is one of the built
コンポーネント x y z です float64 はプリミティブ型のデータ型ビルドで
in primitive data types available to you in creating custom messages.
カスタムメッセージの作成に使用できます
To get more information about the built in types and message definitions in general,
一般的なタイプとメッセージの定義にあるビルドについて詳しい情報を取得するには
check out the links in the text module accompanying the screencast.
スクリーンキャストに付いているテキストモジュールのリンクを参照してください
While ros message info is a very useful tool for getting information about messages,
rosmsg info はメッセージに関する情報を得るにはとても便利なツールですが
it does not tell us everything we may wish to know.
知りたいことがすべてわかるわけではありません
Another tool at your disposal is rosed.
rosed も使いやすいツールです
Rosed is a simple bash command that allows you to
rosed はシンプルな bash コマンドで
easily view and edit files in your ros environment.
ros 環境内のファイルを簡単に表示して編集できます
Let's use it to view the twist message definition.
これを使って Twist メッセージの定義を表示しましょう
Once again I'm going to clear this terminal and then I'm going to
ターミナルをもう一度クリアします
execute the command rosed followed by geometry
コマンド rosed を実行して次に geometry_msgs
underscore messages the name of the package containing the message in
問題のメッセージを含むパッケージの名前です
question followed by twist.msg,
それから twist.msg
the name of the message definition you wish to open.
表示するメッセージ定義の名前です
Note, that if you've forgotten either the package name or the name of the message type,
ここでヒントです パッケージ名やメッセージタイプの名前を思い出せないときは
tab completion will come to the rescue.
タブ完了が役に立ちます
All right here we go. It's the actual message definition.
さて このとおり実際のメッセージ定義が表示されました
It looks very similar to the output we saw from the rosmessage info command.
rosmsg info コマンドの出力とよく似ていますが
Except there are a couple of important differences.
いくつか大切なポイントが違います
The first thing you might notice is that there are
1 つ目は それぞれの Vector3 メッセージ定義について
no details about how each vector 3 message is defined.
詳細がありません
This detail is elsewhere,
この詳細は別のところ
particularly within the vector 3.msg file also living within this package.
特に Vector3.msg ファイル内と このパッケージ内にあります
The rosmessage info command was simply doing us
rosmsg info コマンドは
the favor of expanding the definitions in the console output.
コンソール出力の定義を拡張してくれるだけです
The second thing you might notice are the comments.
2 つ目は コメントです
This is the true reason that we came here.
今までの内容はこのためにあります
When in doubt go to the source code.
不明な点はソースコードを参照してください
Rosmessage info didn't tell us anything about
rosmsg info では Twist メッセージが実際はどのように使用されるかは
how the twist message is actually intended to be used.
まったくわかりませんが
But the friendly ros developer who created this message has our back.
メッセージを作成した親切な ROS 開発者がサポートしてくれます
Most of the message type definitions that are part of
標準の ROS ディストリビューションに含まれるメッセージタイプ定義では
the standard ros distribution have a wealth of
たいていの場合
comments explaining how they are meant to be used.
使い方についてさまざまにコメントされています
Here you can see that the twist messages are actually intended
この Twist メッセージは 実のところ線形速度ベクトルと角速度ベクトルを
to contain linear and angular velocity vectors.
含むようになっているのがわかります
This is something that might have been clear from the usage,
使い方から明らかなのはこういうところです
after all we saw that these messages were being passed around on the cmd_vel topic,
こうしたメッセージは cmd_vel トピックの周辺でやり取りされていますが
but it was not something that was clear from looking at
rosmsg show コマンドの出力から
the output of the rosmsg show command.
わかる内容ではありません
Once again, when in doubt check the source code.
繰り返しますが 不明な点はソースコードを参照してください
This will be a common theme in ros development.
これは ROS 開発では一般的なテーマです